<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wilson Zhao</title>
    <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wilson Zhao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 11:21:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.wilsonzhao.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kalbi</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/kalbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 11:21:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/kalbi/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Things you should always have: Onions, garlic, green onions, water, black pepper Soy Sauce Brown Sugar Mirin/Sake Asian pear/other fruit Seasame Oil  Directions  Make marinade. Cover rib with sugar first. Ratio: for every 5 lb of short rib:  5 lb short ribs 1 cup brown sugar 0.5 cup water 0.25 cup sake 1 onion 1 asian pear minced garlic to taste black pepper   Marinate for 5 hours to overnight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flume Greenpeace Lead</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/flume_greenpeace_lead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 21:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/flume_greenpeace_lead/</guid>
      <description>What a beautiful and haunting synth. Jaw dropped when I first heard this song. Starts at 0:25.
Ingredients  Osc: Saw  Attack: 190ms Delay: 583ms Sustain: -52dB (?) Release: 200ms (?).    Instructions  There&amp;rsquo;s some crazy pitch bend going on. Have a env pitch bend up into each note. Mono + portomento w/~200ms.  Also applied the same env to a wavetable position on a sq/saw wave in the future, sounds sick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paella</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/paella/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 21:12:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/paella/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Things you should always have: onions, garlic, olive oil, butter, S&amp;amp;P, chicken stock  1/2-1 white onion, &amp;gt;=3 cloves garlic, 1.5 cups chicken stock   Aromatics: paprika, saffron, bay leaves 1.7 cups rice 1 regular can of pureed tomatoes 1 big chorizo (maybe a lb?) 1-2 boneless chicken thighs (maybe half lb?) Lemon slices (optional)  Instructions  Dice onions. Sweat onions on medium high with oil, maybe 5-10 mins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ratatouille</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/cookbook-ratatouille/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 16:44:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/cookbook-ratatouille/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients  Things you should always have: onions, garlic, olive oil, butter, S&amp;amp;P, chicken stock Aromatics: rosemary, thyme 4 tomatoes/6 roma tomatoes 1 green squash 1 yellow squash 1 zuccinni Assorted colored peppers  Directions  Mandolin veggies at 1/8&amp;rdquo;? The thinner it is, the fancier it is. Use a sharp knife on tomatoes instead. Submerge tomatoes boiling water for 30s to make them easier to peel. Red Pepper Soup  Knob of butter + olive oil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube to Stems</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/youtube-to-stems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/youtube-to-stems/</guid>
      <description>After 5 (or is it 6?) months of social isolation, I realized I had an overflowing surplus of time. After a brief relapse into Warcraft III, I decided that surplus time could be better invested elsewhere. That &amp;ldquo;elsewhere&amp;rdquo; turned out to be music.
I wanted to get better at sound design and learn how to recreate song I like. Yesterday, I had an epiphany: I knew how to code. The following script takes a youtube URL and extracts the stems&amp;ndash;vocals, bassline, drums, and other stuff&amp;ndash;into a predetermined folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solo Travel: Why?</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/solo-travel-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 20:39:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/solo-travel-why/</guid>
      <description>Context I recently embarked on a journey circumnavigating the world from 1/3/19 to 4/15/19. By writing this series of blog posts, I hope to accomplish several things:
 This blog post serves as a way to unpackage all the thoughts floating rent-free in my head, patiently waiting to be captured by the written word. If I don&amp;rsquo;t write these down, they&amp;rsquo;re going to fade away. It also serves as some sort of guide to future solo travelers (and my colleagues) who have asked me to document some of the findings on my trip, so that they would not repeat the same mistakes I did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solo Travel: How?</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/solo-travel-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 20:07:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/solo-travel-how/</guid>
      <description>On Onebagging It is impractical to lug a 50-pound suitcase if you&amp;rsquo;re constantly moving across country lines. You want the option to carry all your shit with you. Dragging a suitcase across cobblestone streets and over muddy rivers really detracts from the overall travel experience. In addition, if you ever get mugged, you want the option of making a quick getaway. The solution was simple: stuff everything I needed for 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats of the Middle East</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/cats-of-the-middle-east/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 16:35:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/cats-of-the-middle-east/</guid>
      <description>Didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to see many cats in the Middle East.
  Figure 1: Taken at the highest point of Petra, above the monastery.
    Figure 2: Ancient Byzantine Pillars outisde the Ayasofya. Excuse my language, but &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t put pussy on a pedastal.&amp;rdquo;
    Figure 3: Steps in the Christian Quarter of old Jerusalem.
    Figure 4: On a motorcycle outside Bauhaus Hostel in Instanbul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello_worlds</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/hello_worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 18:21:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/blog/hello_worlds/</guid>
      <description>On a bored Saturday, I realized that my old website (with all my iOS app descriptions and occasionally cringey high school blog posts) died when I spilled a cup of free coffee I got from the 6th floor of the Gates-Hillman center at CMU.
Most expensive cup of coffee in my life.
Now that I have a brand new laptop and hopefully much better coffee control, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to create a new website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recipes</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/recipes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 06:42:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/recipes/recipes/</guid>
      <description>Not intended for external consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I attended Mission San Jose High School from 2011-2015.
I attended the School of Computer Science @ Carnegie Mellon University from 2015-2018.
I graduated one semester early to solo travel for 4.5 months.
Currently working @ Google.
I&amp;rsquo;m of a proud owner of a Yamaha Reface CS. Trying to learn sound design and music production.
I was the head TA of 07-131 at Carnegie Mellon University, a class about practical tooling in computer science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wilsonzhao.com/home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>